Preliminary Inventory to the Ralph James Watkins Papers, 1926-1978
Hoover Institution Archives
Ralph James Watkins Papers
1926-1978
80088
Hoover Institution Archives
94 manuscript boxes (39.2 linear feet)
Speeches and writings, studies, reports, memoranda, correspondence, notes, and printed matter, relating to economic planning in the U.S., Mexico, Ecuador, Egypt, India, Taiwan, South Korea, and Japan; and to Allied civil affairs administration in North Africa during World War II.
Watkins, Ralph James, 1896-
Access
Collection stored off site; a minimum of two days notice is required for use. Boxes may be requested through Stanford's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1980.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biography
American economist.
Africa, North.; Africa.; Economists.; Ecuador--Economic policy.; Ecuador.; Egypt--Economic policy.; Egypt.; India--Economic policy.; India.; Japan--Economic policy.; Japan.; Korea (South)--Economic policy.; Korea.; Mexico--Economic policy.; Mexico.; Military government.; Taiwan--Economic policy.; Taiwan.; United States--Economic policy.; United States--Foreign relations.; United States--Politics and government.; World War, 1939-1945--Africa, North.; World War, 1939-1945.
- Boxes 1-47
  - Memoirs of General Antonio Lopez de Santa Anna (Box 1)
  - Letters
  - Miscellaneous writings
  - Printed matter
  - Letters (Box 2)
  - A Study of Overseas Transport and Freight Structure in India's Export Trade
  - A Port Management Problem Study, 1968
  - Role of the United States Merchant Marine Academy in Meeting the Needs of the Maritime Industry, 1968
  - Printed matter
  - Kobe-Nagoya (Japan) Expressway Survey, 1956
    - Correspondence
      - A-T
      - U-Z (Box 3)
      - Newman, J. Wilson
      - Herring, Frank
    - Lists of names, addresses and titles
    - Memoranda
    - Reports
    - Research proposal
    - Agreement
    - Daily record
    - Clippings
    - Japan road map
    - Japan and Japanese language
    - Sheffield, O. A. - Correspondence on Dun family
  - Biographical sketches
  - Photographs
  - Burke and Burke
  - Collector of Customs, New York (Box 4)
  - Certificates
  - Correspondence
    - 1947-1956
    - 1946 (Box 5)
  - Korea
    - Van Fleet material
    - Far East trip, 1954
    - Correspondence, 1952
  - National Planning Association
  - Appointments and invitations
  - Personnel
  - Miscellany
  - Addresses (Box 6)
  - Budget Bureau estimates, 1950
  - Baldwin, Hanson W.
  - Census Advisory Committee, American Statistical Association
  - Census Bureau
    - Test of Dun and Bradstreet coverage
    - Intensive Review Committee, 1953
  - Civil Service Commission
  - Defense Production Administration
  - Downton Association
  - Economic mobilization planning - Columbia University seminar, 1950
  - Election forecasts
  - Gallup poll, 1948
  - Government transportation requests
  - Gross national product
  - Hoover, Edgar M.
  - Intensive Review Committee, 1953
  - Kobe-Nagoya Expressway Survey contract
  - Landry, Robert
  - National Planning Association
  - National Security Resoruces Board
  - New York state
  - Newspaper clippings
  - Port of New York Authority
  - Smith, Jay
  - Speeches
  - Tupper, Ernest
  - Johnson, Lyndon, 1950 (Box 7)
  - Ecuador exports
    - Project report outline, 1963
    - Cost estimates
    - Contract
    - Statistics
    - Printed matter
    - Staff notes (Box 8)
  - Kobe-Nagoya Expressway study, 1956
  - Photographs
  - Drafts of New York Port Authority study
  - The Port of New York Authority: Metropolitan Growth and Structure
  - The Dilemma of Mexico's Development: The Role of the Private and Public Sectors
  - Letters (Box 9)
  - Korea
    - Travel orders and itinerary
    - Van Fleet mission, 1954
  - Transportation (India), 1974
  - Observations on the Revolution in Cargo Handling in Maritime Commerce, 1970
  - Miscellaneous reports (Box 10)
  - Report of the Commission on Major Ports (India), Vol. I, 1970
  - Printed matter
  - Sufragi, Mohamed Ibrahim
  - Memoranda and notes (Box 11)
  - Brookings Institution
  - Transportation and National Policy, 1942
  - Correspondence, 1971-1972
  - Progress reports
  - Norms memorandum, 1972
  - Committee for Farm Mechanization (Korea)
  - American economy
  - Japan lectures, 1976
  - Cairo - Maps, 1975-1976
  - Mackesey, Thomas W.
  - Interviews
  - Study of the Domestic Transport of India's Export Cargo, 1971
  - Children and Adolescents: Goals and Priorities for the Second Development Decade, 1972
  - Evaluation of the Kobe-Nagoya Expressway Survey, 1957 (Box 12)
  - Survey of Overseas Transport and Freight Structure in India's Export Trade: Summary Supplement, 1970
  - Eastern Region Transport Survey: Summary and Recommendations (India), 1967
  - Brookings Institution reprints
  - Farm Mechanization Project (Korea), 1972
  - Eastern Region Transport Survey: Summary and Recommendations (India), Vol. I, 1967
  - Current NPA Research Projects, 1974
  - Printed matter
  - Far East documents, 1948-1952
  - Transportation and National Policy, 1942 (Box 13)
  - Port of New York Authority
  - Moore, Marlin W.
  - India
    - Terms of reference
    - Miscellany and outline
    - Darjeeling, 1966
    - Das, M. R.
  - Sales kit, 1957
  - Personal
  - Exotech Systems contract
  - Correspondence
  - Clippings and notes
  - Budget data
  - Cables
  - Correspondence (Box 14)
  - Outlines
  - India
    - Addresses
    - Baroda project time reports
    - Mormugao Port Trust
    - Cochin Port Trust
  - Miscellany (Box 15)
  - Advisory Committee on Statistical Policy, 1972
  - Kashmir, 1966
  - Memoranda
  - Karcher, Martin
  - Port of New York Authority, 1955-1956
  - What the Southern Tradition Means to Me, 1937
  - Japan, 1956
  - Photographs
  - Development of Resources and Stabilization of Employment in the United States, Parts I-III, 1941
  - Patterns of Resource Use, 1938 (Box 16)
  - Cairo - Correspondence
  - Miscellany (Box 17)
  - Photographs
  - Tippetts-Abbett-McCarthy-Stratton working papers
  - International Bank for Reconstruction and Development correspondence
  - Observations on the Transport Revolution in Japan, 1966
  - Tomei Kosuko Doro, 1969
  - Egypt (Box 18)
    - Miscellany
    - Activities reports
    - Correspondence, 1976-1977
    - Addresses (Box 19)
    - Cables
    - Clippings
    - Abbreviations
    - Montgomery, James M.
    - Binnie Taylor
    - Notes on Possible Effects of Peace upon the Future of Egypt with Special Reference to Possible Physical Improvements, 1978
    - Perkinpine, Ralph W., 1976
    - Personnel, 1977 (Box 20)
    - Pirnie-Harris International
    - Population estimates
      - General
      - Alexandria
      - Cairo
      - Central Agency for Public Mobilization and Statistics
      - Projections
      - Crude birth rate, death rate, and rate of natural increase
      - Helwan
      - Population Reference Bureau 1975 data sheet
    - Port Said land reclamation project
    - Ports seminar
    - Provincial water supply project
    - Management and Tariff Studies Relative to Water and Sewerage Systems, 1978
    - Correspondence (Box 21)
      - 1975
      - 1978
    - Provincial water supply project
    - Plan, 1977
    - Ministry of Industry
    - Memoranda and notes
    - Ministers and their representatives
    - Montasser, Essam
    - Map (Box 22)
    - Ministry of Planning
    - Ministry of Housing and Reconstruction
  - National Economists Club
  - Egypt
    - National development plan, 1977
    - Terms of Reference for a Comprehensive National Urban Growth Policy, 1977
    - New cities
    - Notes on employment projections, 1976
    - The October Working Paper, 1974
  - Pittsburgh Business Review, Vol. I, 1930-1931
  - Eastern Region Transport Survey (India), Vol. III, 1967
  - American Statistical Association - President's folder, 1972
  - An Economic Framework for Project Analysis in India, 1972
  - The Ratnagiri Fisheries Project (India), 1972
  - Eastern Region Transport Survey (India), 1967 (Box 23)
    - Vol. IV
    - Vol. V, Part 1
  - Regional Transport Surveys: Summary (India), 1968
  - Farm Mechanization Program for Korea, 1972
  - This Is Exotech
  - Letters
  - National Transportation Policy Elements, 1974 (Box 24)
  - Building a New Japan, 1974
  - List of overseas assignments
  - Observations on the Revolution in Cargo Handling in Maritime Commerce, 1970
  - Biographical sketches
  - City Population Issues and Strategies in the Middle East, 1978
  - Memos from Egypt, 1975
  - Calendars, 1975-1977
  - Miscellany
  - Survey of the Domestic Transport of India's Export Cargo, Vols. II-IV, 1971 (Box 25)
  - Eastern Region Transport Survey (India), Vol. V, Parts 1-2, 1967
  - Eastern Region Transport Survey (India), 1967 (Box 26)
    - Vol. IV, Part 2
    - Vols. VI-VII
  - Projection of Demand for Steel in Mexico, 1963-1970
  - Proposed Research Program of the Brookings Institution for 1958-64
  - Regional Transport Surveys: Summary (India), 1968
  - Egypt
    - Operating costs
    - Personnel lists
    - Organizations
    - Wage/salary surveys
  - Miller, Raymond W. (Box 27)
  - Reflections from the Kobe-Nagoya Expressway Survey Seventeen Years Later, 1973
  - Egypt
    - National economic setting, 1975
    - The National Economic Framework for the Development of Sadat City, 1976
    - Report notes
    - Economic and Social Development Plan for 1977
    - Work program, 1975
    - Ministry of Maritime Transport
    - Warren, Peter (Box 28)
    - Cairo: Third World Metropolis, 1973
    - The Fisheries Sector, 1975
  - Wyoming, University of
  - Egypt
    - White, Gilbert F.
    - Memoranda
    - Measurements and weights
    - Land reclamation, 1976
    - New Jobs Needed, 1975
    - Issues and questions
    - Ismailia trip, 1975
    - Investments - Law 43
    - Ilaco report, 1975
    - G.O.P.P. reports
    - Ford Foundation
    - Economics and population task force
    - Deadlines ahead, 1975
    - Reply to DAG's Criticism of Our Projections, 1975
    - Cremer, A. C.
    - Computer procedures, 1976
    - City/area team reports
    - The Relationship between Short Run and Long Run Planning
    - Transportation Planning Work for December Report on Regional Plan, 1975
    - U.S. Embassy
    - Entrances to Cairo
    - Weights and measures
    - Suez Canal Zone Regional Plan
  - American firms
  - Egypt
    - American firms
    - Agriculture (Box 29)
  - Consulting Services in Latin America in Technical Cooperation Programs of IDB, 1976
  - Egypt
    - Brown, David - Interview, 1978
    - Building trades - Manpower training
    - Cables
    - Crude birth, death and natural increase rates
    - Canal Zone industrial pilot project
    - Chart - Ministry of Housing and Reconstruction
    - Charts, Data for
    - Bogle, James
    - Black and Veatch
    - Binnie Taylor
    - The Five-Year Plan, 1978-1982, Vol. I, 1977
    - Family planning
    - Economic Management in a Period of Transition - Drafts
  - American Statistical Association
  - Egypt
    - Ameriyah project, 1977
    - Arab contractors
    - Anderson, Arthur
    - Joint task forces, 1975 (Box 30)
    - Ismailia status report #2
    - Irrigation Ministry
    - Initial city/area reports, 1974
    - Foreign trade
    - Compound rates of growth
    - Bibliography, 1975
    - Balance of payments
    - Employment projections, 1975
    - The Egyptian Economy, 1975
    - Aswan High Dam, 1975
    - Alternative strategies
    - Alternative models
    - Accounting
    - Abu Tartur phosphate project
    - Census report (in Arabic)
    - Clippings
    - Benson, Don (Box 31)
    - Cresap, McCormick and Paget
    - Energy study, 1978
    - Engineering News-Record, 1978
    - ES - Parsons
    - Exchange rates
    - Farm mechanization project
    - Integrated agricultural development feasibility study
    - Agriculture
    - Alexandria water facilities
    - Consultants
    - Contacts re economy
    - Construction firms
  - Cosmos Club
  - Egypt
    - Cremer, A. C.
    - Urban Planning in Egypt
    - Demonstration projects
    - Doxiadis Associates project
    - Economic Intelligence Unit
    - Central Agency for Public Mobilization and Statistics
    - Law of regions
    - Letters
    - Library
    - List of administrative units
    - Advisory Committee for Reconstruction
    - Economy
    - Economic regions, 1977
    - Free zones (Box 32)
    - Engineering Consulting Firms Association
    - Agency for International Development
    - Al Ahram
    - Census report (in English), 1976
    - Ministry of Electricity
    - Egypt-U.S. Business Council meetings, 1977
  - India
    - Bank property sale
    - Baum, Warren C.
    - Eschenberg, Horst (Box 33)
    - Cables
    - Singh, Tarlok
    - Anderson, Rex S.
    - Bonded warehouse stocks
    - Cameron, M. A.
    - Costs, Transport (Box 34)
    - Customs exemption problem
    - Eastern railway tour, 1965
    - Economic Importance of the Eastern Area of India
    - Field trips
    - Fourth plan suggestions
    - Ford Foundation
    - Ganguli, M. K., 1966
    - Ghosh, A. K.
    - Haldia port project
    - Harral, Clell G.
    - Instructions re MS preparation
    - Jansen, John A.
    - Jute and tea exports
    - Library lists
    - Memoranda
    - Newspaper clippings
    - Office memoranda
    - Outlines
    - Miscellany (Box 35)
    - Auction, 1967
    - Bank property
    - Sale documents
    - Adler, Hans
    - Air traffic projections and analysis
    - Bell, Bernard R.
    - Chamber of horrors
    - Commodity studies
    - Focal point surveys
    - Ghosh, A. K.
    - Heckhuis, Dale, report
    - International Bank for Reconstruction and Development
    - Indian Institute of Management
    - Industrial survey
    - Jalan, B. L.
  - Japan
  - India
    - Joint Technical Group for Transport Planning
    - Karcher, Martin
    - Loans of books and reports
    - Methodology
    - Metropolitan transport study
    - Minerals
    - Owen, Wilfred
    - Prasad, Ishwari
    - Railway board
    - Secretarial staff
    - Aspects of Methodology for Transport Planning in the Eastern Region, 1966
    - Southeastern railway tour, 1965
    - Speech notes
    - Staff meetings
    - Taxes
    - Transport, Study Group on
    - Tobin, Austin J.
    - Work programs
  - Fitzgerald, D. A. (International Cooperation Administration), 1957
  - Whiteside, A. D., 1952
  - Miscellany
  - Eastern Region Transport Survey (India), Vol. I, 1967
  - Correspondence, 1943-1955 (Box 36)
  - Lectures, 1953
  - Foreign Trade 301 class, 1955-1956
  - Miscellany
  - Excerpts from the Log: Trip to the Far East Command, 1952
  - Cultural Briefing for Taiwan, 1954
  - Economic Mobilization, 1950
  - Psychological Surveys in Business Forecasting, 1954
  - Activities, 1957-1958 (Box 37)
    - Arden House Conference on Consumers, 1958
    - Public service and other professional activities, 1958
    - General
    - American Statistical Association
      - General
      - Budget Bureau Advisory Committee on Statistical Policy
      - Census Advisory Committee (Box 38)
    - Cosmos Club
    - Dun and Bradstreet
    - Federal Statistics Users' Conference
    - Federal Statistics Users' Conference (Box 39)
    - Forecasters Club of New York
    - Harvard University
    - Japan
    - National Planning Association
      - General
      - Business Committee
      - Special Policy Committee on Nuclear Energy
    - National Science Foundation (Box 40)
      - Research and Development Conference, 1958
      - General, 1958
      - Advisory Panel, 1958
    - New York Economists Council (C.I.T.)
    - New York Metropolitan Region Study Advisory Committee
    - North African Economic Board
    - Port of New York Authority (Box 41)
    - Social Science Research Council
      - General
      - Board of Directors
      - Committee on Analysis of Economic Census Data
      - Committee on International Conference Travel Grants, 1958
      - Directors meeting, 1958
    - University Club
    - Brookings Conference, Merrill Center for Economics, 1958
  - Correspondence, 1956
    - National Association of Manufacturers Nuclear Energy Committee
    - Council of Population and Housing Census Users (Box 42)
    - Ohio State University Research Foundation
    - General
      - A-R
      - S-Z (Box 43)
  - Correspondence, 1955
    - Cleveland Engineering Society
    - Committee on Research in Finance
    - General
      - A-G
      - H-W (Box 44)
      - X-Z (Box 45)
  - Correspondence, 1954
    - A-P
    - Q-Z (Box 46)
  - Correspondence, 1957
    - National Association of Manufacturers Nuclear Energy Committee
    - General
      - A-H
      - I-W (Box 47)
  - Miscellany
  - Statement on H.R. 8487 (census legislation), 1954
  - Foreign Economic Administration correspondence, 1943-1944
  - Algiers, 1943-1944
    - Personal
    - Moroccan adjustment
    - Second settlement
- Boxes 48-94
  - National Security Resources Board (Box 48)
    - Reorganization
    - 1948
    - General
  - Intensive Review Committee
    - General
    - Newspaper items
  - Mayor's Advisory Council (New York), 1957
  - Committee on Statistical Program for the City of New York, 1956 (Box 49)
  - Committee on Statistical Program for the City of New York, 1955
  - India (Box 50)
    - Parike, Ashok
    - Petroleum
    - Planning Commission, New Delhi
    - Population data
    - Progress reports, 1966
    - Road transport
    - Sau, Ranjit K.
    - Staff
    - Surveys and Research Corporation
    - United Nations Development Programme, New Delhi
    - Verma, H. L.
    - Ziegler, Heinz
    - Correspondence
  - Photographs
  - A Statistical Program for the Department of Health of the City of New York, 1955 (Box 51)
  - SWECO
  - Economic Management in a Period of Transition (Egypt)
  - Suez Canal Regional Plan: Natural Resources, Mineral Resources and Related Industries, 1976
  - Wyoming, University of
  - Weights and measures - Conversions
  - Upper Egypt trip, 1975
  - Printed matter
  - Preparation and Appraisal of Transport Projects, 1968
  - Exhibits to the Report of the Intensive Review Committee to the Secretary of Commerce on the Programs, Policies and Procedures of the Bureau of the Census, Part 2, 1954 (Box 52)
  - An Approach to Better Understanding of Vietnamese Society, 1962
  - A Study of Administration in Binh Minh District (Vietnam), 1961
  - The Organization and Support of Scientific Research and Development in Mainland China, 1970
  - The Market for Steel in Mexico, 1964
  - Toward Enlarging the Sphere of Freedom, 1951
  - Directory of Selected Scientific Institutions in Mainland China, 1970
  - Tippetts-Abbett-McCarthy-Stratton employment agreement, 1975 (Box 53)
  - Van Fleet, James A.
  - Sufragi, Mohamed Ibrahim
  - Pictures and certificates
  - Personnel
  - Miscellany
  - Pilot Research Projects in Growth Centers (India), 1969-1970
  - India and the 1970's
  - Report of the Commission on Major Ports (India), Part 2, 1970
  - Generalisation de la Reduction de la Duree du Travail, Report V, Part 4, 1938
  - Reduction of Hours of Work in Coal Mines, Item 6, 1939
  - Appraisal of Census Programs, 1954
  - Projections of Demand for Steel in Mexico, 1963-1970
  - Technical Tripartite Meeting on the Coal-Mining Industry, Part 2, 1938 (Box 54)
  - Reunion Technique Tripartite pour l'Industrie Charbonniere, Part 3, 1938
  - Industrial and Commercial Ohio, Vols. I-II, 1928
  - Expanding Ecuador's Exports, 1967 (Box 55)
  - The Construction Industry in Ohio, 1926
  - Ohio Employment Studies, 1927
  - Farm Mechanization Program for Korea, 1972
  - Size Composition of American Business Concerns Listed in the Reference Book (Dun and Bradstreet), 1950
  - Population Changes Cast Long Shadows, 1957
  - Japan's Economy: Bright Spot or Trouble Spot?, 1957
  - Speeches (Box 56)
    - The Move toward Marketing: Framework of Economic and Social Trends, 1957
    - The Years Ahead: Economic Perspectives, 1957
    - Japan, 1957
    - What We Can Do to Overcome Deficiencies in Federal Statistical Programs, 1957
    - Industrial Marketers of Detroit speech, 1956
    - New York Forecasters Club speech, 1956
    - Employers Association of New Jersey speech, 1956
    - National Paint, Varnish and Lacquer Association speech, 1956
    - The Business Outlook, 1956-1966
    - Associated Merchandising Corporation speech, 1956
    - Confession of Faith, 1955
    - Measuring Businessmen's Expectations, 1955
    - Northwestern University seminar on transportation, 1955
    - The Long Look Ahead, 1955
    - The Economic Outlook, 1955 (Box 57)
    - 1955 Business Outlook
    - Testimony before U.S. Congress Joint Committee on the Economic Report, 1955
    - Regional Managers Meeting, 1954
    - Real Estate Round Table, 1954
    - Industrial Marketers of Detroit speech, 1954
    - Regional Service Managers speech, 1954
    - Dun's Review and Modern Industry speech, 1954
    - Southwest Credit Conference, 1954
    - Boston Conference on Distribution, 1954
    - The United States Economy: Where Do We Go from Here?, 1954
    - National Association of Home Builders symposium, 1954
    - Observations on the Far East, 1954
    - American Marketing Association seminar, 1954
    - Economic Outlook, 1954
    - The President's Program, 1954
    - Philadelphia Bulletin forum, 1954 (Box 58)
    - The Long Look Ahead, 1954
    - The Economic Outlook, 1954
    - Sticking My Neck Out, 1953
    - The Economic Outlook, 1953
    - National Planning Association speech, 1953
    - The Outlook in Korea, 1953
    - The Prospects in Korea, 1953
    - The Outlook in the Korean War, 1953
    - The Outlook in the Korean War, 1953 (Box 59)
    - Perspective on the American Economy, 1953
    - Observations on the Korean War, 1952
    - Toward Enlarging the Sphere of Freedom, 1951
    - Mobilizing American Industry and Resources, 1950
    - Speeches, 1945-1949
    - Industrial Decentralization: General Considerations, 1947
    - Miscellaneous speeches
    - Korean War speech cards
    - Speech materials
    - Stories for speeches
    - Speech cards (Box 60)
  - University of Hong Kong Symposium on Economic and Social Problems of the Far East, 1961
  - Printed matter
  - Letters
  - Letters (Box 61)
  - Photographs
  - The Framework of an Economy of Plenty, 1942
  - National Resources Planning Board
  - Certificates
  - Letters (Box 62)
  - Photographs
  - Miscellany
  - Activities (Box 63)
    - Federal Statistics Users' Conference
      - General
      - Annual meeting, 1959
    - Census Users' Council Meeting, 1959
    - Arden House Conference on Strategy for Peace, 1960 (Box 64)
    - Brookings Institution Economic Specialists Group, 1960-1962
    - American Statistical Association Census Advisory Committee
    - American Statistical Association Census Advisory Committee, 1959 (Box 65)
  - Calendars, 1953-1956
  - Addresses
  - Personal Income of the New York Metropolitan Region, 1958 (Box 66)
  - International Labour Office Technical Tripartite Meetings on the Coal-Mining Industry, 1938
  - Kathmandu, Nepal, 1970
  - National Science Foundation Annual Meeting of Chairmen of Divisional Committees and Office Advisory Committees, 1961
  - Taiwan
    - Economic indicators
    - Economic Stabilization Board
    - Educational program
    - A Review of Existing Foreign Exchange and Trade Control Policy and Technique, 1959 (Box 67)
    - Governmental structure
    - China Development Corporation
  - Social Science Research Council Census Committee
  - Taiwan (Box 68)
    - China Productivity and Trade Center